Eu...
Eu vou vingar o Archer.
Apesar de tudo,
ele ainda era o meu parceiro.
Eu também.
Já decidi que vou lutar.
Se eu não for até o fim com isso, ele nunca me deixaria em paz.
Além disso, não podemos simplesmente deixar o Graal intacto.
Ele precisa ser destruído.
Eu concordo.
Um milagre que reúne os desejos de todos, mas aceita apenas um,
nunca deveria ter existido.
Saber...
Mas você estaria de acordo com isso, Rin?
Não é o sonho mais acalentado da família Tohsaka obter o Graal?
It is, but I don't want some monkey's paw of a weapon.
I never really had a wish I wanted granted, anyway.
And smashing it will be cathartic in its own way.
I didn't enter the Holy Grail War for the spoils. Only to win.
To hold my head high as a Tohsaka.
Sim.
É a sua cara dizer isso.
Como assim é a minha cara?
Nem faz sentido!
Muito bem.
Sh-Shirou?
O-O que foi?
Ah, pensei em fazer algo para comermos.
Vocês duas devem estar com fome.
A pressa é inimiga da perfeição, não é?
Vamos começar enchendo a barriga e avaliando nossas opções.
Sim, é verdade.
Vamos jantar como de costume.
É assim que sempre fizemos as coisas.
Acho que você tem razão.
Okay, I'll help out.
The Holy Grail is at Ryuudou Temple?
Yes.
There are three places in town
where the Grail can be manifested.
My home,
Kirei's church,
and Ryuudou Temple on Mt. Enzou.
I sent familiars to each, and the one at Ryuudou Temple was smashed.
It's safe to assume that flashy gold jerk is setting up camp at Ryuudou Temple.
Doesn't that mean Issei and the others there are in danger?
Look at this.
Everyone there was taken away in ambulances?
Right.
This means that any interlopers have been removed ahead of time.
Shinji's doing, no doubt.
It's the kind of move I'd expect a wary guy like him to make,
but in this case, it's a godsend.
Ryuudou Temple, though... That will prove problematic.
With its anti-spirit barrier,
Servants can only enter through the main gate.
On the upside, knowing exactly where the Grail will be is good for us.
After all, our first priority is to stop its summoning.
Saber will take the main gate.
She'll keep him occupied out front,
and as she does, we'll climb the mountain from the back and destroy the Grail.
Hang on...
Isn't Saber the only one who can destroy it?
Good point.
Once the Grail's summoned, we won't be able to destroy it.
But we can destroy its vessel before then.
Basically, we shut down the Grail before it can activate.
What do you mean?
Judging by the events up until now,
you would assume the Holy Grail is Illyasviel's heart, right?
But I think it also needs her body—
or rather, magic circuits—to function.
He didn't want Illyasviel to become the Grail,
so he only removed the core: her heart.
Therefore, for it to function,
he needs to implant it into another mage's body.
Since the two of us are here,
his choice for the Grail's foundation has to be...
Shinji?
But he isn't, well...
Even if the Matou mage lineage has died out,
they still have latent magic circuits.
Illyasviel's heart would forcibly open even those.
Which means that we have to start by locating Shinji.
Then I need to distract Archer until you two stop the Grail?
Yes.
And as soon as we stop the Grail, we'll come running.
No, that's crazy.
Saber's no match for him.
On what grounds do you base that assessment, Shirou?
Uh... As a swordsman, he's no match for you,
but no matter how skilled the warrior, they can't defeat war itself.
He's that kind of Heroic Spirit.
You also have to be war itself, or you'll be swallowed whole.
So you are saying that I would be at a disadvantage against him?
That's why we can't send Saber to fight him without a plan, Tohsaka.
We need to figure out his weakness, at least.
Like you said, his Noble Phantasm is war itself,
and on top of that, he's a Servant specialized in killing Heroic Spirits.
To beat him, you'd need to have an armory to equal his...
What?
Why did you stop mid-sentence?
I see.
That's why he always treated him like a sworn enemy.
Right, a Heroic Spirit without his own Noble Phantasm
wouldn't have an original weapon.
It'll work...
This will work!
Hang on, that would mean...
If you have something to say, spit it out.
You have an idea, right?
I do not!
I can't tell you here, you idiot!
Rin?
Anyway, the existing plan should be fine.
We carry it out before dawn, got it?
Until then, everyone should go to their rooms and get plenty of rest.
Also, I need to discuss something with you, Saber.
You're okay with this, Saber?
Yes. I think it the best option.
You have my thanks, Rin.
This will allow me to fight without undue concern as well.
What do you want?
What do I...
Did I catch you in a really bad mood or something?
No, not really. It's not like that.
What's your problem, then?
Do you have a fever or something?
Of course I don't!
Jeez... Just come in already.
Let me guess, you're here for another stupid reason?
Tohsaka, what were you and Saber...
What?
No, forget it.
Just hear me out and don't get mad.
I want to—
You want to fight him, don't you?
Oh? So you figured it out.
That the natural enemy of Gilgamesh's Noble Phantasm is Archer's magic.
It is?
Huh? Hang on...
You came up with that hare-brained suggestion without even figuring that much out?
No, I just had a gut feeling that I'd have the best chance out of the three of us.
Well, your gut isn't wrong.
What makes Gilgamesh the most powerful is the
overwhelming number of Noble Phantasms he has.
Furthermore, for every anti-Heroic-Spirit weapon there is, he has the original.
But there is no Noble Phantasm legendary for killing Archer.
Most of all, given sufficient mana,
he could match anyone weapon for weapon.
Gilgamesh called you two "fakes,"
but I'll bet that was because he actually saw you as threats.
Because unlike others, he would have to fight Heroic Spirit Emiya on equal footing.
There's a flaw in your plan, though.
My projections won't be able to keep up with his barrage of Noble Phantasms,
and my mana won't last.
Yes, if your magic stays at its current level.
But you remember Archer's Noble Phantasm, right?
If you could master that magic—
that Reality Marble—you could hold your own against Gilgamesh.
That's crazy.
I don't have that kind of mana.
Well, several options come to mind.
But the one I'm thinking of...
is a method that links two mages, along with their stores of mana.
You mean creating a path between you and me to share mana?
Yes.
Even if you don't have the mana to use a Reality Marble, I do.
I'll have you use my mana to fight Gilgamesh.
Now, as for how to establish that path...
Tohsaka?
I'm going to transplant my magic crest onto you.
But isn't that...
Isn't the magic crest considered a mage's ultimate legacy?
That's right.
The current family head takes magic that was originally formless and shapes it over the course of their life.
It's the heritage of a mage family,
handed down from generation to generation.
I can't take something that means so much to you.
It's fine.
This is my most important fight,
so I have to commit my most important possession, right?
Why are you staring at me like that?
Sorry. I was just in awe of you for a second.
I know it's kinda late to say this,
but that's what made me fall for you.
F-Fall for me?
This is hardly the time for sweet talk!
But if you want to keep going,
I guess I could force myself to listen.
Yeah, I know.
There's not much time.
Okay, let's start the transplant.
What do you need me to do, Tohsaka?
Well, start by getting undressed...
What's wrong?
Look, don't get any funny ideas!
I only said to take your clothes off, got it?
I'm taking mine off too, so it's all fair.
You're undressing too?
L-Like I said, don't get the wrong idea!
Getting undressed is to facilitate the transfer of body heat.
That's all there is to it!
Listen. To transplant a magic crest,
we need to enter a state of deep rapport.
Oh, I get it.
Um, just my top is okay, right?
Obviously!
I'm going to begin.
Tohsaka!
Did it work?
Tohsaka?
Of course it worked.
It was so flawless there's nothing to critique.
So precise there won't be any aftereffects.
So perfect that even Kirei, who specialized in this stuff,
would compliment me and say,
"That was fine work, my disciple."
So this is...
Yes.
It's the magic crest I transplanted onto you.
This will give you more than enough mana to create a Reality Marble.
So the rest...
That's up to me.
Thanks, Tohsaka.
But why are you so angry?
You saw it, didn't you?
Hang on, did I do something?
You saw it, didn't you? You brute!
I don't know what you're talking about, but I'm sure you're wrong!
My eyes were closed the whole time,
and the only thing I saw were some images that looked like magic circuits...
Ah, right, Tohsaka.
There was that weird dream...
Like I was in a schoolyard somewhere,
watching some guy doing high jumps like an idiot until the sun set.
What the heck was...
What was that for?
Shut up, shut up, shut up, shut up!
Shut up, shut up!
Don't be so rough on the pillows, you idiot!
Shut up, you brute!
Don't peek at other people's secrets and then act all high and mighty!
Huh? You call that a secret?
Fine, whatever.
I'll get a look at your embarrassing memories sooner or later!
And when I do, I won't hold back, you hear?!
What are you doing, Saber?
A great many things have happened.
I wished to etch them into my mind, so that I might never forget them.
I see.
If you can, I hope you always remember.
I shall.
Also, I must give you my thanks.
Thank you, Shirou.
It took quite some time,
but you have shown me the way.
Saber?
Forgive me. This surely makes no sense to you.
But I wished to put it into words.
One dream has come to an end.
Although I was unable to leave you any example to follow,
you have given me an answer that is more than sufficient.
A dream?
You mean yours?
I cannot say.
Even if it is mine, it is the story of an unknown little girl—
one who no longer has anything to do with me.
I once had a dream.
I have a favor to ask of you as well.
I shall protect the two of you.
So make certain that you both return to this house.
Sure, we'll come back here.
You can count on it.
Let's go settle this once and for all, Saber.
Vomit forth your curses, Holy Grail.
The time has come to judge whether the humans of this era
can withstand the weight of their own wishes.
We'll put an end to your Holy Grail right now!
With Caster gone, you should not still be here!
I'm not good enough to fend off his Noble Phantasms.
You filthy sham.
Learn firsthand the difference
between counterfeits and the real thing!
Gib dem wandernden Vogel das Trinkwasser,
der vom langen Weg kommt.
Benutz den Vogelrahmen
in dem der Schlüssel nicht angewendet wird.
Ich spinne den Regenbogen in neuem selbst.
Heißes Wetter, Regen,
Wind, Schnee, Krieg, Ende, ununterbrochen.
Nimm an, ohne anderer Meinung zu sein, ohne zu fallen.
Es nimmt an, ohne zu fürchten,
ohne zu zweifeln.
Sieg im Freund, der auf eine Reise entfernt geht.